require 'colorize'

user1 = User.create(username: "felipe", password: "felipep")
user2 = User.create(username: "john", password: "johnp")
user3 = User.create(username: "steve", password: "stevep")
user4 = User.create(username: "jack", password: "jackp")
user5 = User.create(username: "sam", password: "samp")
user6 = User.create(username: "ben", password: "benp")
user7 = User.create(username: "barry", password: "barryp")
user8 = User.create(username: "eliot", password: "eliotp")
user9 = User.create(username: "adnan", password: "adnanp")
user10 = User.create(username: "bijan", password: "bijanp")
user11 = User.create(username: "terry", password: "terryp")
user13 = User.create(username: "emily", password: "emilyp")

question1 = Question.create(question: "In 1954, Vietnam defeated which nation to gain their independence?".blue, option_a: "France", option_b: "United States", option_c: "Great Britain", correct_answer: "France", correct_answer_response: "Correct. On May 7, 1954, the French-held garrison at Dien Bien Phu in Vietnam fell after a four month siege led by Vietnamese nationalist Ho Chi Minh. After the fall of Dien Bien Phu, the French pulled out of the region.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. On May 7, 1954, the French-held garrison at Dien Bien Phu in Vietnam fell after a four month siege led by Vietnamese nationalist Ho Chi Minh. After the fall of Dien Bien Phu, the French pulled out of the region.".blue)
question2 = Question.create(question: "Which German city suffered what was later called the 'Hiroshima of Germany' by British officials?".blue, option_a: "Dresden", option_b: "Hamburg", option_c: "Berlin", correct_answer: "Hamburg", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Codenamed Operation Gomorrah, the bombing of Hamburg was a campaign of Allied air raids beginning 24 July, 1943 and lasting for 8 days and 7 nights. It was at the time the heaviest assault in the history of aerial warfare. On July 24, 2,326 tons of bombs were dropped in just 43 minutes. 46,000 civilians would perish. Then 19 year old Kate Hoffmeister was one of the civilians in Hamburg that night. She recalls her experience 'The rain of large sparks, blowing down the street, were each as large as a five-mark piece. I struggled to run against the wind but could only reach a house on the corner of the Sorbenstrasse... [We] couldn’t go on across the Eiffestrasse because the asphalt road had melted. There were people on the roadway, some already dead, some still lying alive but stuck in the asphalt. They must have rushed onto the roadway without thinking. Their feet had got stuck and then they had put out their hands to try to get out again. They were on their hands and knees screaming.'".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Codenamed Operation Gomorrah, the bombing of Hamburg was a campaign of Allied air raids beginning 24 July, 1943 and lasting for 8 days and 7 nights. It was at the time the heaviest assault in the history of aerial warfare. On July 24, 2,326 tons of bombs were dropped in just 43 minutes. 46,000 civilians would perish. Then 19 year old Kate Hoffmeister was one of the civilians in Hamburg that night. She recalls her experience 'The rain of large sparks, blowing down the street, were each as large as a five-mark piece. I struggled to run against the wind but could only reach a house on the corner of the Sorbenstrasse... [We] couldn’t go on across the Eiffestrasse because the asphalt road had melted. There were people on the roadway, some already dead, some still lying alive but stuck in the asphalt. They must have rushed onto the roadway without thinking. Their feet had got stuck and then they had put out their hands to try to get out again. They were on their hands and knees screaming.'".blue)
question3 = Question.create(question: "Which year marked the end of British rule on the Indian subcontinent?".blue, option_a: "1944", option_b: "1947", option_c: "1952", correct_answer: "1947", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The British Crown ruled the Indian subcontinent from 1858 to 1947.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. The British Crown ruled the Indian subcontinent from 1858 to 1947.".blue)
question4 = Question.create(question: "The first successful vaccine was introduced by Edward Jenner in 1796. Which disease did it guard against?".blue, option_a: "Smallpox", option_b: "Measles", option_c: "Hepatitis B", correct_answer: "Smallpox", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Edward Jenner was an English physician and scientist who was the pioneer of the smallpox vaccine, the world's first vaccine.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Edward Jenner was an English physician and scientist who was the pioneer of the smallpox vaccine, the world's first vaccine.".blue)
question5 = Question.create(question: "In 1970, Venera 7 became the first spacecraft to successfully land on another planet and transmit data back to Earth. Which planet did it land on?".blue, option_a: "Mars", option_b: "Jupiter", option_c: "Venus", correct_answer: "Venus", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Venera 7 was a Soviet spacecraft, part of the Venera series of probes to Venus. When it landed on the Venusian surface, it became the first spacecraft to land on another planet and first to transmit data from there back to Earth.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Venera 7 was a Soviet spacecraft, part of the Venera series of probes to Venus. When it landed on the Venusian surface, it became the first spacecraft to land on another planet and first to transmit data from there back to Earth.".blue)
question6 = Question.create(question: "Which famous first was achieved by Constance Markievicz on 14th December 1918?".blue, option_a: "First woman to be elected to the British House of Commons", option_b: "First woman to fight in the British Army", option_c: "First woman to fly across the English Channel", correct_answer: "First woman to be elected to the British House of Commons", correct_answer_response: "Correct. She was the first woman to be elected to the British House of Commons (she did not, however, take her seat – Nancy Astor was the first to do so in 1919).".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. She was the first woman to be elected to the British House of Commons (She did not, however, take her seat – Nancy Astor was the first to do so in 1919).".blue)
question7 = Question.create(question: "Who is the only Prime Minister of the United Kingdom to have been assassinated?".blue, option_a: "Clement Attlee", option_b: "Spencer Perceval", option_c: "Bonar Law", correct_answer: "Spencer Perceval", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Spencer Perceval served as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom from October 1809 until his assassination in May 1812. At 5:15 pm, on the evening of 11 May 1812, Perceval was on his way to attend the inquiry into the Orders in Council. As he entered the lobby of the House of Commons, a man stepped forward, drew a pistol and shot him in the chest. Perceval fell to the floor, after uttering something that was variously heard as 'murder' and 'oh my God'.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Spencer Perceval served as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom from October 1809 until his assassination in May 1812. At 5:15 pm, on the evening of 11 May 1812, Perceval was on his way to attend the inquiry into the Orders in Council. As he entered the lobby of the House of Commons, a man stepped forward, drew a pistol and shot him in the chest. Perceval fell to the floor, after uttering something that was variously heard as 'murder' and 'oh my God'.".blue)
question8 = Question.create(question: "Which Roman Emperor oversaw the initiation of the 'Pax Romana', or Roman Peace, a long period of hegemonial peace and stability (without wars, expansion or revolts) experienced by the early Roman Empire?".blue, option_a: "Julius Caesar", option_b: "Caesar Augustus", option_c: "Pompey the Great", correct_answer: "Caesar Augustus", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The Pax Romana is traditionally dated as commencing from the accession of Caesar Augustus. Augustus was Julius Caesar's nephew, a military leader and the first emperor of the Roman Empire, coming to power after Caesar's assassination. Reigning from 27 BC until his death in AD 14, his status as the founder of the Roman Principate has consolidated an enduring legacy as one of the most effective and controversial leaders in human history.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. The Pax Romana is traditionally dated as commencing from the accession of Caesar Augustus. Augustus was Julius Caesar's nephew, a military leader and the first emperor of the Roman Empire, coming to power after the power struggle following Caesar's assassination. Reigning from 27 BC until his death in AD 14, his status as the founder of the Roman Principate has consolidated an enduring legacy as one of the most effective and controversial leaders in human history.".blue)
question9 = Question.create(question: "Which Carthaginian General took Rome by surprise and crossed the Alps with his entire Army (elephants included) to confront Rome in mainland Italy?".blue, option_a: "Hamalcar", option_b: "Hannibal", option_c: "Hampsicora", correct_answer: "Hannibal", correct_answer_response: "Nice, you got it. In just 16 days, Hannibal Barca terrified Rome by doing what most Romans thought to be impossible, crossing the freezing, unforgiving Alps along with his 30,000 soldiers, 37 elephants and 15,000 horses, achieving one of the most celebrated achievements of any military force in ancient warfare in the process.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky. In just 16 days, Hannibal Barca terrified Rome by doing what most Romans thought to be impossible, crossing the freezing, unforgiving Alps along with his 30,000 soldiers, 37 elephants and 15,000 horses, achieving one of the most celebrated achievements of any military force in ancient warfare in the process.".blue)
question10 = Question.create(question: "Which city did Anne Frank live in while she wrote her WWII diaries?".blue, option_a: "Paris", option_b: "Berlin", option_c: "Amsterdam", correct_answer: "Amsterdam", correct_answer_response: "Correct. In early July 1942, after Anne's sister Margot received a letter ordering her to report to a work camp in Germany, Anne Frank's family went into hiding in an attic apartment behind Otto Frank's business, located at Prinsengracht 263 in Amsterdam.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. In early July 1942, after Anne's sister Margot received a letter ordering her to report to a work camp in Germany, Anne Frank's family went into hiding in an attic apartment behind Otto Frank's business, located at Prinsengracht 263 in Amsterdam.".blue)
question11 = Question.create(question: "In which city was Archduke Franz Ferdinand assassinated in 1914?".blue, option_a: "Sarajevo", option_b: "Vienna", option_c: "Belgrade", correct_answer: "Sarajevo", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand of Austria, heir presumptive to the Austro-Hungarian throne, and Franz Ferdinand's wife Sophie, Duchess of Hohenberg, occurred on 28 June 1914 in Sarajevo when they were mortally wounded by Gavrilo Princip, triggering a series of events which would eventually lead to the outbreak of the First World War.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. The assassination of Archduke Franz Ferdinand of Austria, heir presumptive to the Austro-Hungarian throne, and Franz Ferdinand's wife Sophie, Duchess of Hohenberg, occurred on 28 June 1914 in Sarajevo when they were mortally wounded by Gavrilo Princip, triggering a series of events which would eventually lead to the outbreak of the First World War.".blue)
question12 = Question.create(question: "The ancient cities of Pompeii and Herculaneum were almost entirely destroyed in A.D. 79 due to the eruption of which volcano?".blue, option_a: "Mount Etna", option_b: "Monte Nuovo", option_c: "Mount Vesuvius", correct_answer: "Mount Vesuvius", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The destruction of Pompeii and Herculaneum occurred in A.D. 79, when, after a century of inactivity, Mount Vesuvius unleashed voluminous clouds of hot gas and ash along with rock and pyroclastic flows that entombed Herculaneum and Pompeii, killing an estimated 30,000 people.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. The destruction of Pompeii occurred in A.D. 79, when, after a century of inactivity, Mount Vesuvius unleashed voluminous clouds of hot gas and ash along with rock and pyroclastic flows that entombed Herculaneum and Pompeii, killing an estimated 30,000 people.".blue)
question13 = Question.create(question: "During a restoration period beginning in 1868, Japan began to open its ports to international trade. Carrying swords in public became prohibited and the samurai class was dissolved. What was this restoration period called?".blue, option_a: "The Samurai restoration", option_b: "The Meiji restoration", option_c: "The Bushido restoration", correct_answer: "The Meiji restoration", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The Meiji restoration. This was a period that restored practical imperial rule to the Empire of Japan in 1868 under Emperor Meiji. Although there were ruling emperors before the Meiji Restoration, the events restored practical abilities and consolidated the political system under the emperor of Japan.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "It was actually the Meiji restoration. This was a period that restored practical imperial rule to the Empire of Japan in 1868 under Emperor Meiji. Although there were ruling emperors before the Meiji Restoration, the events restored practical abilities and consolidated the political system under the emperor of Japan.".blue)
question14 = Question.create(question: "In George Orwell's '1984', the nation of Oceania has a terrifying motto, what was that motto?".blue, option_a: "War is Peace. Freedom is Slavery. Ignorance is Strength.", option_b: "War is Freedom. Freedom is War. Ignorance is Weakness.", option_c: "War is Strength. Strength is War. Ignorance is Bliss.", correct_answer: "War is Peace. Freedom is Slavery. Ignorance is Strength.", correct_answer_response: "Correct. A nice and easy one. This was such a good book from the legend himself. Might give it another read!".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky. It was actually 'War is Peace. Freedom is Slavery. Ignorance is Strength'. If you haven't read '1984' yet, please give it a read!".blue)
question15 = Question.create(question: "During the First World War, a Canadian doctor was inspired by the sight of poppies growing in battle-scarred fields to write a now famous poem called 'In Flanders Fields'. What was his name?".blue, option_a: "Lieutenant John McCrae", option_b: "Lieutenant Luc St-Pierre", option_c: "Lieutenant Evan McDonald", correct_answer: "Lieutenant John McCrae", correct_answer_response: "Correct. It was indeed Lieutenant John McCrae. Here is his poem: 'In Flanders Field the poppies blow. Between the crosses, row on row. That mark our place; and in the sky. The larks, still bravely singing, fly. Scarce head amid the guns below. We are the Dead. Short days ago. We lived, felt dawn, saw sunset glow. Loved and were loved, and now we lie. In Flanders fields. Take up our quarrel with the foe: To you from failing hands we throw. The torch; be yours to hold it high. If ye break faith with us who die. We shall not sleep, though poppies grow. In Flanders fields.'".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky. It was actually Lieutenant John McCrae. Here is his poem: 'In Flanders Field the poppies blow. Between the crosses, row on row. That mark our place; and in the sky. The larks, still bravely singing, fly. Scarce head amid the guns below. We are the Dead. Short days ago. We lived, felt dawn, saw sunset glow. Loved and were loved, and now we lie. In Flanders fields. Take up our quarrel with the foe: To you from failing hands we throw. The torch; be yours to hold it high. If ye break faith with us who die. We shall not sleep, though poppies grow. In Flanders fields.'".blue)
question16 = Question.create(question: "After the conclusion of the Battle of Stalingrad during WWII, the Russian Red Army captured 91,000 German POWs from the German 6th Army. Of these 91,000, how many made it back home to Germany after the end of the War?".blue, option_a: "21,000", option_b: "37,000", option_c: "6,000", correct_answer: "6,000", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Only 6,000 out of the 91,000 Stalingrad POWs made it back to Germany after the War. During the months that followed their capture, weakened by disease (particularly typhus), malnutrition, and mistreatment, POWs died by the thousands. Here is a Christmas diary entry from German soldier William Hoffman, before their capture: 'The horses have already been eaten. I would eat a cat; they say its meat is also tasty. The soldiers look like corpses or lunatics, looking for something to put in their mouths. They no longer take cover from Russian shells; they haven't the strength to walk, run or hide. A curse on this war!'".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky this time. Only 6,000 out of the 91,000 Stalingrad POWs made it back to Germany after the War. During the months that followed their capture, weakened by disease (particularly typhus), malnutrition, and mistreatment, POWs died by the thousands. Here is a Christmas diary entry from german soldier William Hoffman, before their capture: 'The horses have already been eaten. I would eat a cat; they say its meat is also tasty. The soldiers look like corpses or lunatics, looking for something to put in their mouths. They no longer take cover from Russian shells; they haven't the strength to walk, run or hide. A curse on this war!'".blue)
question17 = Question.create(question: "In William Shakespeare's 'The Tragedy of Julius Caesar', which character says the following line: 'Between the acting of a dreadful thing, and the first motion, all the interim is like a phantasma or a hideous dream'?".blue, option_a: "Julius Caesar", option_b: "Brutus", option_c: "Cassius", correct_answer: "Brutus", correct_answer_response: "Yes, Brutus utters this amazing line as he ponders his plot to murder Caesar (somewhat of a Father figure to him) with his servant Lucius. Amazing line, wouldn't expect anything less from the master himself.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "It was actually Brutus. He utters this amazing line as he ponders his plot to murder Caesar (somewhat of a Father figure to him) with his servant Lucius. Amazing line, wouldn't expect anything less from the master himself.".blue)
question18 = Question.create(question: "The 369th Infantry Regiment was an infantry regiment of the New York National Guard during World War I & World War II. It was known for being the first African American regiment to serve with the American Expeditionary Forces during World War I. They were given a nickname by the Germans due to their toughness and the fact that they never lost a man through capture, nor a trench or a foot of ground to the enemy during the entirety of their participation in the First World War. What was this nickname?".blue, option_a: "The Harlem Hellfighters", option_b: "The New York Rattlers", option_c: "The Men of Steel", correct_answer: "The Harlem Hellfighters", correct_answer_response: "Yes, the Harlem Hellfighters. Throughout WWI, the 369th spent 191 days in frontline trenches, more than any other American unit. They also suffered the most losses of any American regiment with 1,500 casualties. Before the 369th was formed, any black American that wanted to fight in WWI had to enlist in the French or Canadian armies. The French nicknamed the 369th the 'Men of Bronze' in WWI and the Regiment also included a number of Puerto Rican Americans during World War II.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky, it was actually the Harlem Hellfighters. Throughout WWI, the 369th spent 191 days in frontline trenches, more than any other American unit. They also suffered the most losses of any American regiment with 1,500 casualties. Before the 369th was formed, any black American that wanted to fight in WWI had to enlist in the French or Canadian armies. The French nicknamed the 369th the 'Men of Bronze' in WWI and the Regiment also included a number of Puerto Rican Americans during World War II.".blue)
question19 = Question.create(question: "Which famous historical figure is credited with the quote: 'You cannot stop me, I spend 30,000 men a month.'?".blue, option_a: "Julius Caesar", option_b: "Adolf Hitler", option_c: "Napoleon Bonaparte", correct_answer: "Napoleon Bonaparte", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Napoleon warned the Austrian statesman Metternich, 'I spend 30,000 men a month'. With most of Europe moving against them, France had to look at new options – which came in the form of pioneering the adoption of Total War. This means mobilising all of a country’s resources, both infrastructure and civilian, to support the war effort.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky. It was Napoleon who warned the Austrian statesman Metternich, 'I spend 30,000 men a month'. With most of Europe moving against them, France had to look at new options – which came in the form of pioneering the adoption of Total War. This means mobilising all of a country’s resources, both infrastructure and civilian to support the war effort.".blue)
question20 = Question.create(question: "The Soviet RDS-202 hydrogen bomb, known by Western nations as the 'Tsar Bomba', was the most powerful nuclear weapon ever created. What was its yield?".blue, option_a: "50 megatons of TNT", option_b: "25 megatons of TNT", option_c: "35 megatons of TNT", correct_answer: "50 megatons of TNT", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The Tsar Bomba unleashed almost unbelievable energy – now widely agreed to be in the order of 50 megatons, or 50 million tons of TNT. That is more than 1,500 times that of the Hiroshima and Nagasaki bombs combined, and 10 times more powerful than all the munitions expended during World War Two!".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky. The Tsar Bomba unleashed almost unbelievable energy – now widely agreed to be in the order of 50 megatons, or 50 million tons of TNT. That is more than 1,500 times that of the Hiroshima and Nagasaki bombs combined, and 10 times more powerful than all the munitions expended during World War Two!".blue)
question21 = Question.create(question: "Who was the only boxer to knock out Muhammad Ali?".blue, option_a: "Joe Frazier", option_b: "Larry Holmes", option_c: "Sonny Liston", correct_answer: "Larry Holmes", correct_answer_response: "Yes, Larry Holmes knocked out Ali in 1980, in the 10th round of a bout billed as 'The Last Hurrah'. Frazier did knock Ali down at times during their bouts, but never knocked him out.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Larry Holmes knocked out Ali in 1980, in the 10th round of a bout billed as 'The Last Hurrah'. Frazier did knock Ali down at times during their bouts, but never knocked him out.".blue)
question22 = Question.create(question: "Which of Oliver Cromwell sons ruled England in 1658-59.".blue, option_a: "Richard Cromwell", option_b: "Henry Cromwell", option_c: "Robert Cromwell", correct_answer: "Richard Cromwell", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Oliver Cromwell died on 3 September 1658, and Richard was informed on the same day that he was to succeed him. Some controversy surrounds the succession. A letter by John Thurloe suggests that Cromwell nominated his son orally on 30 August, but other theories claim either that he nominated no successor, or that he put forward Charles Fleetwood, his son-in-law.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Oliver Cromwell died on 3 September 1658, and Richard was informed on the same day that he was to succeed him. Some controversy surrounds the succession. A letter by John Thurloe suggests that Cromwell nominated his son orally on 30 August, but other theories claim either that he nominated no successor, or that he put forward Charles Fleetwood, his son-in-law.".blue)
question23 = Question.create(question: "What was the American codename for the development of the atom bomb?".blue, option_a: "The Atom Project", option_b: "The Manhattan Project", option_c: "The Chicago Project", correct_answer: "The Manhattan Project", correct_answer_response: "Yes, the Manhattan Project. Colonel James C. Marshall headed the US Army's part of the project. Marshall created a liaison office in Washington, D.C., but established his temporary headquarters on the 18th floor of 270 Broadway in New York. It was close to the Manhattan office of Stone & Webster, the principal project contractor.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "It was the Manhattan Project. Colonel James C. Marshall headed the US Army's part of the project. Marshall created a liaison office in Washington, D.C., but established his temporary headquarters on the 18th floor of 270 Broadway in New York. It was close to the Manhattan office of Stone & Webster, the principal project contractor.".blue)
question24 = Question.create(question: "Who were the Celtic-speaking peoples living in France & Belgium during Roman Times?".blue, option_a: "The Gauls", option_b: "The Vizigoths", option_c: "The Carthaginians", correct_answer: "The Gauls", correct_answer_response: "The Gauls were a group of Celtic peoples of Western Europe in the Iron Age and the Roman period (roughly from the 5th century BC to the 5th century AD). The area they inhabited was known as Gaul. The Romans saw the Gauls as a tough, war-like people. Julius Caesar eventually conquered the whole of Gaul by 51 BC.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "The Gauls were a group of Celtic peoples of Western Europe in the Iron Age and the Roman period (roughly from the 5th century BC to the 5th century AD). The area they inhabited was known as Gaul. The Romans saw the Gauls as a tough, war-like people. Julius Caesar eventually conquered the whole of Gaul by 51 BC.".blue)
question25 = Question.create(question: "Which infamous controversial structure went up in 1961 and came down in 1991?".blue, option_a: "Al Wakrah Stadium", option_b: "The Portland Building", option_c: "The Berlin Wall", correct_answer: "The Berlin Wall", correct_answer_response: "That was an easy one. Construction of the Wall was commenced by the German Democratic Republic (GDR, East Germany) on 13 August 1961. The Wall cut off West Berlin from surrounding East Germany, including East Berlin. It eventually came down in November 1991.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "That should've been an easy one. Construction of the Wall was commenced by the German Democratic Republic (GDR, East Germany) on 13 August 1961. The Wall cut off West Berlin from surrounding East Germany, including East Berlin. It eventually came down in November 1991.".blue)
question26 = Question.create(question: "What was the name of the river Julius Caesar crossed with his army when he finally decided to precipitate the Roman Civil War, which ultimately led to him becoming dictator?".blue, option_a: "The Tiber River", option_b: "The Rubicon River", option_c: "The Brenta River", correct_answer: "The Rubicon River", correct_answer_response: "As his term of governorship in Gaul (modern-day France & Belgium) ended, the Roman Senate ordered Caesar to disband his army and return to Rome. He was explicitly ordered not to bring his army across the Rubicon river, which was at that time a northern boundary of Italy. In January of 49 BC, Caesar, afraid of the many prosecution cases which awaited him in Rome, brought the 13th legion across the river, which the Roman government considered insurrection, treason, and a declaration of war on the Roman Senate. Today, the phrase 'crossing the Rubicon' is a metaphor that means to pass a point of no return.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky. As his term of governorship in Gaul (modern-day France & Belgium) ended, the Roman Senate ordered Caesar to disband his army and return to Rome. He was explicitly ordered not to bring his army across the Rubicon river, which was at that time a northern boundary of Italy. In January of 49 BC, Caesar, afraid of the many prosecution cases which awaited him in Rome, brought the 13th legion across the river, which the Roman government considered insurrection, treason, and a declaration of war on the Roman Senate. Today, the phrase 'crossing the Rubicon' is a metaphor that means to pass a point of no return.".blue)
question27 = Question.create(question: "Which London landmark marks the starting point for the Great Fire of London?".blue, option_a: "The Tower of London", option_b: "Nelson's Column", option_c: "The Monument", correct_answer: "The Monument", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The Monument to the Great Fire of London, more commonly known simply as the Monument, is a Doric column located in Monument Square, London. The first Rebuilding Act, passed in 1669, stipulated that 'to better preserve the memory of this dreadful visitation, a column of either brass or stone should be set up on Fish Street Hill, on or near the site of Farynor's bakery, where the fire began'".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. The Monument to the Great Fire of London, more commonly known simply as the Monument, is a Doric column located in Monument Square, London. The first Rebuilding Act, passed in 1669, stipulated that 'to better preserve the memory of this dreadful visitation, a column of either brass or stone should be set up on Fish Street Hill, on or near the site of Farynor's bakery, where the fire began.''".blue)
question28 = Question.create(question: "Which European country remained neutral throughout the Second World War despite the Germans bombing its capital city in May 1941 by accident?".blue, option_a: "Ireland", option_b: "Switzerland", option_c: "Belgium", correct_answer: "Ireland", correct_answer_response: "Nice. As part of the United Kingdom, Northern Ireland was at war, but the independent state of Ireland was neutral. In 31 May 1941, German bombers accidentally dropped four bombs on north Dublin, killing 28 people. After the war, what became West Germany accepted responsibility for the raid, and by 1958 it had paid compensation of £327,000.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky, it was Ireland. As part of the United Kingdom, Northern Ireland was at war, but the independent state of Ireland was neutral. In 31 May 1941, four German bombs fell on north Dublin, killing 28 people. After the war, what became West Germany accepted responsibility for the raid, and by 1958 it had paid compensation of £327,000.".blue)
question29 = Question.create(question: "Which historical leader was known as the Scourge of God?".blue, option_a: "Joseph Stalin", option_b: "Ghenghis Khan", option_c: "Atilla the Hun", correct_answer: "Atilla the Hun", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Attila was king of the Huns, a non-Christian people based on the Great Hungarian Plain in the fifth century A.D. At its height, the Hunnic Empire stretched across Central Europe. The Romans considered the Huns to be barbarians, and under Attila’s rule the Huns pillaged and destroyed many Roman cities. By the time of his death in A.D. 453, Attila had become known as the “Scourge of God,” and his death was cheered in what was left of the Roman Empire.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky. Attila was king of the Huns, a non-Christian people based on the Great Hungarian Plain in the fifth century A.D. At its height, the Hunnic Empire stretched across Central Europe. The Romans considered the Huns to be barbarians, and under Attila’s rule the Huns pillaged and destroyed many Roman cities. By the time of his death in A.D. 453, Attila had become known as the “Scourge of God,” and his death was cheered in what was left of the Roman Empire.".blue)
question30 = Question.create(question: "Which British Admiral defeated the French at the Battle of Trafalgar, but was killed during the battle?".blue, option_a: "Edward Dyke Acland", option_b: "Horatio Nelson", option_c: "Edward Stanley Adeane", correct_answer: "Horatio Nelson", correct_answer_response: "That was an easy one. Nelson died during the Battle of Trafalgar in south-west Spain on 21 October 1805 at around 1-2pm. He took the fatal bullet while pacing the quarterdeck of his ship HMS Victory with Captain Thomas Hardy.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Better luck next time. Horatio Nelson died during the Battle of Trafalgar in south-west Spain on 21 October 1805 at around 1-2pm. He took the fatal bullet while pacing the quarterdeck of his ship HMS Victory with Captain Thomas Hardy".blue)
question31 = Question.create(question: "Which Italian island was the first place of exile of Napoleon?".blue, option_a: "Elba", option_b: "Capri", option_c: "Procida", correct_answer: "Elba", correct_answer_response: "Correct. In the Treaty of Fontainebleau, the Allies exiled Napoleon to Elba, an island of 12,000 inhabitants in the Mediterranean, 12 miles off the Tuscan coast. They gave him sovereignty over the island and allowed him to retain the title of Emperor. Napoleon attempted suicide with a pill he had carried after nearly being captured by the Russians during his retreat from Moscow. Its potency had weakened with age, however, and he survived to be exiled, while his wife and son took refuge in Austria. In the first few months on Elba he created a small navy and army, developed the iron mines, oversaw the construction of new roads, issued decrees on modern agricultural methods, and overhauled the island's legal and educational system. On February 26, 1815, Napoleon managed to sneak past his guards and somehow escape from Elba, slip past interception by a British ship, and return to France.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky. In the Treaty of Fontainebleau, the Allies exiled Napoleon to Elba, an island of 12,000 inhabitants in the Mediterranean, 12 miles off the Tuscan coast. They gave him sovereignty over the island and allowed him to retain the title of Emperor. Napoleon attempted suicide with a pill he had carried after nearly being captured by the Russians during his retreat from Moscow. Its potency had weakened with age, however, and he survived to be exiled, while his wife and son took refuge in Austria. In the first few months on Elba he created a small navy and army, developed the iron mines, oversaw the construction of new roads, issued decrees on modern agricultural methods, and overhauled the island's legal and educational system. On February 26, 1815, Napoleon managed to sneak past his guards and somehow escape from Elba, slip past interception by a British ship, and return to France.".blue)
question32 = Question.create(question: "Who in 1961 made the first space flight?".blue, option_a: "Alexei Leonov", option_b: "Yuri Gagarin", option_c: "Neil Armstrong", correct_answer: "Yuri Gagarin", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Gagarin's capsule, Vostok 1, completed one orbit of Earth on 12 April 1961. Gagarin became an international celebrity and was awarded many medals and titles, including Hero of the Soviet Union, his nation's highest honour.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky. Yuri Gagarin's capsule, Vostok 1, completed one orbit of Earth on 12 April 1961. Gagarin became an international celebrity and was awarded many medals and titles, including Hero of the Soviet Union, his nation's highest honour.".blue)
question33 = Question.create(question: "Which battle of 1066 shares its name with a Premier League football ground?".blue, option_a: "Stamford Bridge", option_b: "The Molineux Stadium", option_c: "Old Trafford", correct_answer: "Stamford Bridge", correct_answer_response: "Nice! The Battle of Stamford Bridge took place at the village of Stamford Bridge, East Riding of Yorkshire, in England on 25 September 1066, between an English army under King Harold Godwinson and an invading Norwegian force led by King Harald Hardrada and the English king's brother Tostig Godwinson. Chelsea's stadium shares the same name as the battle.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Nice! The Battle of Stamford Bridge took place at the village of Stamford Bridge, East Riding of Yorkshire, in England on 25 September 1066, between an English army under King Harold Godwinson and an invading Norwegian force led by King Harald Hardrada and the English king's brother Tostig Godwinson. Chelsea's stadium shares the same name as the battle.".blue)
question34 = Question.create(question: "What was the nickname given to famed German Field Marshal Erwin Rommel during the Second World War?".blue, option_a: "The Blonde Beast", option_b: "The Wolf", option_c: "The Desert Fox", correct_answer: "The Desert Fox", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Field Marshal Rommel was one of Germany's most popular generals during World War II, and gained his enemies' respect with his victories as commander of the Afrika Korps, where his was given his nickname, 'The Desert Fox'. Implicated in a plot to overthrow Hitler, Rommel was given the option of facing a public trial for treason as a co-conspirator in the plot to assassinate the Führer, or taking cyanide. In the former case, his family would have suffered even before the all-but-certain conviction and execution, and his staff would have been arrested and executed as well. In the latter case, the government would claim that he died a hero and bury him with full military honours. He choose the latter and committed suicide on October 14, 1944.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Unlucky. Field Marshal Rommel was one of Germany's most popular generals during World War II, and gained his enemies' respect with his victories as commander of the Afrika Korps, where his was given his nickname, 'The Desert Fox'. Implicated in a plot to overthrow Hitler, Rommel was given the option of facing a public trial for treason as a co-conspirator in the plot to assassinate the Führer, or taking cyanide. In the former case, his family would have suffered even before the all-but-certain conviction and execution, and his staff would have been arrested and executed as well. In the latter case, the government would claim that he died a hero and bury him with full military honours. He choose the latter and committed suicide on October 14, 1944.".blue)
question35 = Question.create(question: "In the US Civil War did Britain support the Confederacy, the Union, or did it remain neutral?".blue, option_a: "Union", option_b: "Confederacy", option_c: "Neutral", correct_answer: "Neutral", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland remained officially neutral throughout the American Civil War (1861–1865). The British elite tended to support the Confederacy, but ordinary people tended to support the United States, or the Union. Great Britain legally recognised the belligerent status of the Confederate States of America but never recognised it as a nation and neither signed a treaty with it nor ever exchanged ambassadors.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland remained officially neutral throughout the American Civil War (1861–1865). The British elite tended to support the Confederacy, but ordinary people tended to support the United States, or the Union. Great Britain legally recognised the belligerent status of the Confederate States of America but never recognised it as a nation and neither signed a treaty with it nor ever exchanged ambassadors.".blue)
question36 = Question.create(question: "In which year did the Titanic sink?".blue, option_a: "1912", option_b: "1910", option_c: "1918", correct_answer: "1912", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The RMS Titanic sank in the early morning of 15 April 1912 in the North Atlantic Ocean, four days into the ship's maiden voyage from Southampton to New York City. The largest ocean liner in service at the time, the Titanic had an estimated 2,224 people on board when she struck an iceberg at around 23:40 (ship's time). The estimated death toll ranges from 1,490 to 1,635.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. The RMS Titanic sank in the early morning of 15 April 1912 in the North Atlantic Ocean, four days into the ship's maiden voyage from Southampton to New York City. The largest ocean liner in service at the time, the Titanic had an estimated 2,224 people on board when she struck an iceberg at around 23:40 (ship's time). The estimated death toll ranges from 1,490 to 1,635.".blue)
question37 = Question.create(question: "Who was Spain's dictator from 1939 until his death in 1975?".blue, option_a: "Miguel Primo de Rivera", option_b: "Francisco Franco", option_c: "Francisco Gómez-Jordana", correct_answer: "Francisco Franco", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Francisco Franco Bahamonde ruled over Spain as Head of State and dictator under the title 'Caudillo' from 1939, after the Nationalist victory in the Spanish Civil War, until his death in 1975.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Francisco Franco Bahamonde ruled over Spain as Head of State and dictator under the title 'Caudillo' from 1939, after the Nationalist victory in the Spanish Civil War, until his death in 1975.".blue)
question38 = Question.create(question: "Barbarossa was the German codename for the invasion of which country in the Second World War?".blue, option_a: "France", option_b: "Soviet Union", option_c: "Poland", correct_answer: "Soviet Union", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Operation Barbarossa was the code name for the Axis invasion of the Soviet Union, which started on Sunday, 22 June 1941. The operation stemmed from Nazi Germany's ideological aim of conquering the western Soviet Union so that it could be repopulated by Germans. Germany launched the operation with an initial frontline strength of 3.8 million personnel, with an unprepared Soviet Union putting 2.6-2.9 million men at the frontline defenses. By Barbarossa's end, Germany had sustained 1 millon military casualties, and the Soviet Union a staggering 4.97 million. All of this in roughly 5 months. Unbelievable.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Operation Barbarossa was the code name for the Axis invasion of the Soviet Union, which started on Sunday, 22 June 1941. The operation stemmed from Nazi Germany's ideological aim of conquering the western Soviet Union so that it could be repopulated by Germans. Germany launched the operation with an initial frontline strength of 3.8 million personnel, with an unprepared Soviet Union putting 2.6-2.9 million men at the frontline defenses. By Barbarossa's end, Germany had sustained 1 millon military casualties, and the Soviet Union a staggering 4.97 million. All of this in roughly 5 months. Unbelievable.".blue)
question39 = Question.create(question: "Which is the bloodiest battle in the history of warfare?".blue, option_a: "Battle of the Somme", option_b: "Mongol Sacking of Baghdad", option_c: "Battle of Stalingrad", correct_answer: "Battle of Stalingrad", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The Battle of Stalingrad was the largest confrontation of World War II, in which Germany and its allies fought the Soviet Union for control of the city of Stalingrad. Marked by fierce close quarters combat and direct assaults on civilians in air raids, it was the largest (nearly 2.2 million personnel) and bloodiest (1.8–2 million killed, wounded or captured) battle in the history of warfare. Fun fact: despite the Mongol Sacking of Baghdad having occurred in 1258 without any modern weaponry, it still resulted in around 2 million casualties. Ghenghis Khan and the Mongols didn't play.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. The Battle of Stalingrad was the largest confrontation of World War II, in which Germany and its allies fought the Soviet Union for control of the city of Stalingrad. Marked by fierce close quarters combat and direct assaults on civilians in air raids, it was the largest (nearly 2.2 million personnel) and bloodiest (1.8–2 million killed, wounded or captured) battle in the history of warfare. Fun fact: despite the Mongol Sacking of Baghdad having occurred in 1258 without any modern weaponry, it still resulted in around 2 million casualties. Ghenghis Khan and the Mongols didn't play.".blue)
question40 = Question.create(question: "In Greek legend, which King turned everything he touched into gold?".blue, option_a: "King Midas", option_b: "King Leonidas", option_c: "King Actaeus", correct_answer: "King Midas", correct_answer_response: "An easy one. King Midas is popularly remembered in Greek mythology for his ability to turn everything he touched into gold. This came to be called the golden touch, or the Midas touch. King Midas was 'rewarded' with this power after entertaining the foster father of Dionysus (god of the grape-harvest, wine, fertility, ritual madness, religious ecstasy, and theatre), Silenus for ten days. Midas initially rejoiced in his new power, but upon discovering that even his food and drink turned into gold in his hands, he regretted his reward and cursed it. The Latin poet Claudian states in his 'In Rufinum': 'So Midas, king of Lydia, swelled at first with pride when he found he could transform everything he touched to gold; but when he beheld his food grow rigid and his drink harden into golden ice then he understood that this gift was a bane and in his loathing for gold, cursed his prayer.'".yellow, wrong_answer_response: "That should've been an easy one. King Midas is popularly remembered in Greek mythology for his ability to turn everything he touched into gold. This came to be called the golden touch, or the Midas touch. King Midas was 'rewarded' with this power after entertaining the foster father of Dionysus (god of the grape-harvest, wine, fertility, ritual madness, religious ecstasy, and theatre), Silenus for ten days. Midas initially rejoiced in his new power, but upon discovering that even his food and drink turned into gold in his hands, he regretted his reward and cursed it. The Latin poet Claudian states in his 'In Rufinum': 'So Midas, king of Lydia, swelled at first with pride when he found he could transform everything he touched to gold; but when he beheld his food grow rigid and his drink harden into golden ice then he understood that this gift was a bane and in his loathing for gold, cursed his prayer.'".blue)
question41 = Question.create(question: "What did Winston Churchill describe as 'a riddle, wrapped in a mystery, inside an enigma'?".blue, option_a: "Hitler", option_b: "Russia", option_c: "World War 2", correct_answer: "Russia", correct_answer_response: "Correct. During a radio broadcast in October 1939, after the german invasion of Poland, Churchill stated 'I cannot forecast to you the action of Russia. It is a riddle, wrapped in a mystery, inside an enigma; but perhaps there is a key. That key is Russian national interest.'".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. During a radio broadcast in October 1939, after the german invasion of Poland, Churchill stated 'I cannot forecast to you the action of Russia. It is a riddle, wrapped in a mystery, inside an enigma; but perhaps there is a key. That key is Russian national interest.'".blue)
question42 = Question.create(question: "Ancient Rome had a military punishment in which every tenth man in a group was executed by nine other fellow soldiers in his cohort. What was this punishment called?".blue, option_a: "Decimation", option_b: "Fustuarium", option_c: "Pecunaria multa", correct_answer: "Decimation", correct_answer_response: "Correct. A cohort (roughly 480 soldiers) selected for punishment by decimation was divided into groups of ten. Each group drew lots, and the soldier on whom the lot of the shortest straw fell was executed by his nine comrades, often by stoning, clubbing, or stabbing. Nasty. The discipline was used by senior commanders in the Roman Army to punish units or large groups guilty of capital offences, such as cowardice, mutiny, desertion, and insubordination, and for pacification of rebellious legions. The word decimation is derived from Latin meaning 'removal of a tenth'.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. A cohort (roughly 480 soldiers) selected for punishment by decimation was divided into groups of ten. Each group drew lots, and the soldier on whom the lot of the shortest straw fell was executed by his nine comrades, often by stoning, clubbing, or stabbing. Nasty. The discipline was used by senior commanders in the Roman Army to punish units or large groups guilty of capital offences, such as cowardice, mutiny, desertion, and insubordination, and for pacification of rebellious legions. The word decimation is derived from Latin meaning 'removal of a tenth'.".blue)
question43 = Question.create(question: "Who destroyed the Great Library of Alexandria?".blue, option_a: "Pompey the Great", option_b: "Ptolemy VIII", option_c: "Julius Caesar", correct_answer: "Julius Caesar", correct_answer_response: "Correct. It is most widely believed that the Library of Alexandria was destroyed in a fire that was started when Caesar burned the Egyptian fleet while he was besieged at Alexandria, Egypt in 48 B.C. during the Great Roman Civil War. The Great Library of Alexandria was one of the largest and most significant libraries of the ancient world. The Library was part of a larger research institution called the Mouseion, which was dedicated to the Muses, the nine goddesses of the arts.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. It is most widely believed that the Library of Alexandria was destroyed in a fire that was started when Caesar burned the Egyptian fleet while he was besieged at Alexandria, Egypt in 48 B.C. during the Great Roman Civil War. The Great Library of Alexandria was one of the largest and most significant libraries of the ancient world. The Library was part of a larger research institution called the Mouseion, which was dedicated to the Muses, the nine goddesses of the arts.".blue)
question44 = Question.create(question: "How many languages did Cleopatra speak?".blue, option_a: "2", option_b: "1", option_c: "4", correct_answer: "2", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Cleopatra VII Philopator was the last active ruler of the Ptolemaic Kingdom of Egypt, her native language was Koine Greek and she was the first Ptolemaic ruler to learn the Egyptian language. After her death in 10 or 12 August 30 BC, she was survived as pharaoh by her son with Julius Caesar, Caesarion. Multiple sources claim she also spoke Ethiopian, Trogodyte, Hebrew (or Aramaic), Arabic, the Syrian language (perhaps Syriac), Median, Parthian, and Latin.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Cleopatra VII Philopator was the last active ruler of the Ptolemaic Kingdom of Egypt, her native language was Koine Greek and she was the first Ptolemaic ruler to learn the Egyptian language, so 2 would've been the right answer. After her death in 10 or 12 August 30 BC, she was survived as pharaoh by her son with Julius Caesar, Caesarion. Some sources claim she also spoke Ethiopian, Trogodyte, Hebrew (or Aramaic), Arabic, the Syrian language (perhaps Syriac), Median, Parthian, and Latin.".blue)
question45 = Question.create(question: "Where did the Incas originate?".blue, option_a: "Mexico", option_b: "Peru", option_c: "Guatemala", correct_answer: "Peru", correct_answer_response: "Correct. The Inca first appeared in what is today southeastern Peru during the 12th century A.D. According to some versions of their own origin myths, they were created by the sun god, Inti, who sent his son Manco Capac to Earth through the middle of three caves called Pacari Tampu.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. The Inca first appeared in what is today southeastern Peru during the 12th century A.D. According to some versions of their own origin myths, they were created by the sun god, Inti, who sent his son Manco Capac to Earth through the middle of three caves called Pacari Tampu.".blue)
question46 = Question.create(question: "Which Russian female sniper was given the nickname 'Lady Death' by the Germans during the Second World War?".blue, option_a: "Aliya Moldagulova", option_b: "Roza Shanina", option_c: "Lyudmila Pavlichenko", correct_answer: "Lyudmila Pavlichenko", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Lyudmila Pavlichenko is regarded as one of the top military snipers of all time and the most successful female sniper in history. She is credited with 309 kills and was nicknamed 'Lady Death'. She survived the war and died at age 58 in 1974. Aliya Moldagulova and Roza Shanina were also famous female Soviet snipers who fought in World War 2, both have been credited with being some of the best snipers the Soviet Union had to offer during the war.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Correct. Lyudmila Pavlichenko is regarded as one of the top military snipers of all time and the most successful female sniper in history. She is credited with 309 kills and was nicknamed 'Lady Death'. She survived the war and died at age 58 in 1974. Aliya Moldagulova and Roza Shanina were also famous female Soviet snipers who fought in World War 2, both have been credited with being some of the best snipers the Soviet Union had to offer during the war.".blue)
question47 = Question.create(question: "Which Roman gladiator led a rebel revolt against the Roman Empire between 73 B.C. and 71 B.C.?".blue, option_a: "Spartacus", option_b: "Priscus", option_c: "Marcus Atilius Regulus", correct_answer: "Spartacus", correct_answer_response: "Correct. That one was easy. Spartacus was a Thracian gladiator who, along with Crixus, Gannicus, Castus, and Oenomaus, was one of the escaped slave leaders in the Third Servile War, a major slave uprising against the Roman Republic. Little is known about Spartacus beyond the events of the war, and surviving historical accounts are sometimes contradictory and may not always be reliable. However, all sources agree that he was a former gladiator and an accomplished military leader.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Spartacus is not just a TV show lol. Spartacus was a Thracian gladiator who, along with Crixus, Gannicus, Castus, and Oenomaus, was one of the escaped slave leaders in the Third Servile War, a major slave uprising against the Roman Republic. Little is known about Spartacus beyond the events of the war, and surviving historical accounts are sometimes contradictory and may not always be reliable. However, all sources agree that he was a former gladiator and an accomplished military leader.".blue)
question48 = Question.create(question: "Who organised the expedition to the East Indies from 1519 to 1522, resulting in the first circumnavigation of the Earth?".blue, option_a: "Ferdinand Magellan", option_b: "Sir Francis Drake", option_c: "Ernest Shackleton", correct_answer: "Ferdinand Magellan", correct_answer_response: "Correct. After having his proposed expeditions to the Spice Islands repeatedly rejected by King Manuel of Portugal, Magellan turned to Charles I, the young King of Spain, to finance his expedition. Magellan's fleet consisted of five ships, carrying supplies for two years of travel. The crew consisted of about 270 men. Most were Spanish, but around 40 were Portuguese. The journey took about 3 years, with hell awaiting the sailors around every corner in the form of starvation, disease, thirst, and at times, native tribes wary of Europeans. Magellan did not live to see the end of the journey as he was killed in an incident involving a native tribe. One of his men, Ginés de Mafra, provides a written account of the events culminating in his death: 'When they wounded him, he turned back many times to see whether we were all in the boats. Thereupon, beholding him dead, we, wounded, retreated, as best we could, to the boats, which were already pulling off.'. The journey was eventually completed by Spanish explorer Juan Sebastián Elcano".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. After having his proposed expeditions to the Spice Islands repeatedly rejected by King Manuel of Portugal, Magellan turned to Charles I, the young King of Spain, to finance his expedition. Magellan's fleet consisted of five ships, carrying supplies for two years of travel. The crew consisted of about 270 men. Most were Spanish, but around 40 were Portuguese. The journey took about 3 years, with hell awaiting the sailors around every corner in the form of starvation, disease, thirst, and at times, native tribes wary of Europeans. Magellan did not live to see the end of the journey as he was killed in an incident involving a native tribe. One of his men, Ginés de Mafra, provides a written account of the events culminating in his death: 'When they wounded him, he turned back many times to see whether we were all in the boats. Thereupon, beholding him dead, we, wounded, retreated, as best we could, to the boats, which were already pulling off.'. The journey was eventually completed by Spanish explorer Juan Sebastián Elcano".blue)
question49 = Question.create(question: "In which city was Joan of Arc burned at the stake for being a witch?".blue, option_a: "Paris", option_b: "Orleans", option_c: "Rouen", correct_answer: "Rouen", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Tied to a tall pillar at the Vieux-Marché in Rouen, Normandy (modern-day France), Joan of Arc asked two of the clergy, Martin Ladvenu and Isambart de la Pierre, to hold a crucifix before her. An English soldier also constructed a small cross that she put in the front of her dress. After she died, the English raked back the coals to expose her charred body so that no one could claim she had escaped alive. They then burned the body twice more, to reduce it to ashes and prevent any collection of relics, and cast her remains into the Seine River. The executioner, Geoffroy Thérage, later stated that he 'greatly feared to be damned for he had burned a holy woman.'".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Tied to a tall pillar at the Vieux-Marché in Rouen, Normandy (modern-day France) Joan of Arc asked two of the clergy, Martin Ladvenu and Isambart de la Pierre, to hold a crucifix before her. An English soldier also constructed a small cross that she put in the front of her dress. After she died, the English raked back the coals to expose her charred body so that no one could claim she had escaped alive. They then burned the body twice more, to reduce it to ashes and prevent any collection of relics, and cast her remains into the Seine River. The executioner, Geoffroy Thérage, later stated that he 'greatly feared to be damned for he had burned a holy woman.'.".blue)
question50 = Question.create(question: "Vietnam's Communist leader Ho Chi Minh was also known by which nickname?".blue, option_a: "Ruthless Ho", option_b: "Uncle Ho", option_c: "Communist Ho", correct_answer: "Uncle Ho", correct_answer_response: "Correct. Ho Chi Minh led the North in the Vietnam War, but died in 1969 before the war ended. His body was preserved and embalmed, against his wishes, and is still on view in Hanoi.".blue, wrong_answer_response: "Incorrect. Ho Chi Minh, also known as Uncle Ho, led the North in the Vietnam War, but died in 1969 before the war ended. His body was preserved and embalmed, against his wishes, and is still on view in Hanoi.".blue)